I am from the South Side of Chicago,
أنا من الجزء الجنوبي لمدينة شيكاغو.
and in seventh grade, I had a best friend named Jenny
وفي الصف السابع، كانت لدي صديقة عزيزة تدعى جيني
who lived on the Southwest Side of Chicago.
كانت تقطن في الجزء الجنوبي الغربي من شيكاغو.
Jenny was white,
كانت جيني من أصحاب البشرة البيضاء،
and if you know anything about the segregated demographics of Chicago,
وإذا كانت لديكم معرفة بالتركيبة السكانية المنفصلة في شيكاغو،
you know that there are not too many black people
ستعلمون أنه لا يوجد الكثير من أصحاب البشرة السمراء
who live on the Southwest Side of Chicago.
ممن يسكنون في جنوب غرب شيكاغو.
But Jenny was my girl
لكن كانت جيني صديقتي
and so we would hang out every so often after school and on the weekends.
وكنا نتسكع سويًا بين الحين والآخر بعد المدرسة وفي عطلة نهاية الأسبوع.
And so one day we were hanging out in her living room,
وذات يوم كنا نجلس سويًا في منزلها،
talking about 13-year-old things,
نتحدث عن أمور تشغل بال من يبلغون 13 عامًا،
and Jenny's little sister Rosie was in the room with us,
وكانت روزي شقيقة جيني الصغيرة معنا في الغرفة،
and she was sitting behind me just kind of playing in my hair,
وكانت جالسة خلفي تعبث بشعري،
and I wasn't thinking too much about what she was doing.
ولم أكترث كثيرًا لما كانت تفعله.
But at a pause in the conversation,
ولكن خلال لحظة صمت أثناء الحوار،
Rosie tapped me on the shoulder.
لمست روزي كتفي.
She said, "Can I ask you a question?"
وقالت: "هل أستطيع أن أطرح عليكي سؤالًا؟"
I said, "Yeah, Rosie. Sure."
قلت لها: "نعم، بالطبع يا روزي"
"Are you black?"
"هل بشرتكِ سمراء؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The room froze.
تجمدت الغرفة.
Silence.
هدوء.
Jenny and Rosie's mom was not too far away.
لم تكن والدة جيني وروزي بعيدة منا.
She was in the kitchen and she overheard the conversation,
كانت بالمطبخ وسمعت حديثنا،
and she was mortified.
وكانت محرجة للغاية.
She said, "Rosie! You can't ask people questions like that."
قالت: "روزي، لا يمكنك أن تسألي مثل هذه الأسئلة."
And Jenny was my friend, and I know she was really embarrassed.
جيني كانت صديقتي، وأعلم أنها كانت محرجة جدًا.
I felt kind of bad for her, but actually I was not offended.
شعرت بالذنب من أجلها، لكن في الواقع لم أشعر بالإهانة.
I figured it wasn't Rosie's fault that in her 10 short years on this earth,
اكتشفت أنه ليس ذنب روزي التي عاشت 10 سنوات على هذه الأرض،
living on the Southwest Side of Chicago,
وتعيش في الجزء الجنوبي الغربي من شيكاغو
she wasn't 100 percent sure what a black person looked like.
أنها لم تكن تعلم تمامًا شكل الشخص صاحب البشرة السمراء.
That's fair.
هذا طبيعي.
But what was more surprising to me was,
لكن الذي أدهشني أكثر
in all of this time I had spent with Jenny and Rosie's family --
في خلال كل هذه الوقت الذي قضيته برفقة عائلة جيني و روزي،
hanging out with them,
وخروجي معهم،
playing with them,
ولعبي معهم،
even physically interacting with them --
وحتى تفاعلي الجسدي معهم،
it was not until Rosie put her hands in my hair
وحتى قبل أن تضع روزي يدها في شعري
that she thought to ask me if I was black.
لتفكر في أن تسألني عما إذا كنت سمراء.
That was the first time I would realize
كانت هذه المرة الوحيدة التي أدرك فيها
how big of a role the texture of my hair played in confirming my ethnicity,
حجم الدور الذي يلعبه نسيج شعري في تحديد عرقي،
but also that it would play a key role in how I'm viewed by others in society.
ولكن أيضًا له دور أساسي في كيفية رؤية الآخرين لي في المجتمع.
Garrett A. Morgan and Madame CJ Walker were pioneers
كان كلًا من جاريت مورجان والسيدة سي جاي والكر من رواد
of the black hair-care and beauty industry in the early 1900s.
صناعة منتجات العناية بالشعر والتجميل في بداية القرن الـ19.
They're best known as the inventors of chemically-based hair creams
وهما معروفان باختراعهما لكريمات الشعر الكيميائية
and heat straightening tools
وأجهزة تنعيم الشعر
designed to permanently, or semipermanently,
مصممة بشكل دائم أو شبه دائم،
alter the texture of black hair.
لتعدل نسيج شعر ذوي البشرة السمراء.
Oftentimes when we think about the history of blacks in America,
غالبًا عندما نفكر بتاريخ أصحاب البشرة السمراء في أمريكا
we think about the heinous acts
نفكر بالأفعال الشنيعة
and numerous injustices that we experienced as people of color
وأنواع الظلم الذي مررنا به كأصحاب بشرة سمراء
because of the color of our skin,
بسبب لون بشرتنا،
when in fact, in post-Civil War America,
بينما في الواقع، في مرحلة ما بعد الحرب الأهلية الأمريكية،
it was the hair of an African-American male or female
كان شعر الأمريكيين من أصل أفريقي من الإناث والذكور
that was known as the most "telling feature" of Negro status,
الذي عُرف بأنه أكثر "سمة دالة" على الزنوج،
more so than the color of the skin.
أكثر من لون البشرة نفسها.
And so before they were staples
وقبل أن يصبحوا مؤسسين
of the multibillion-dollar hair-care industry,
لصناعة مواد العناية بالشعر والتي تقدر إيراداتها بمليارات الدولارات،
our dependency on tools and products,
اعتمادنا على أدوات ومنتجات،
like the hair relaxer and the pressing comb,
مثل زيوت الشعر والأمشاط الضاغطة،
were more about our survival and advancement as a race
كانت تتمحور حول قدرتنا على البقاء والتقدم بصفتنا عرق
in postslavery America.
في فترة ما بعد العبودية في أمريكا.
Over the years, we grew accustomed to this idea
على مر السنين، اعتدنا على فكرة
that straighter and longer hair meant better and more beautiful.
أنه كلما كان الشعر ناعمًا وطويلًا كلما كان أكثر جمالًا وحُسنًا.
We became culturally obsessed
وأصبحنا مولعين بها في المجتمع
with this idea of having what we like to call ...
بأن فكرة اقتناء ما نحب تسميته
"good hair."
بـ"الشعر الجيد."
This essentially means:
وهذا يعني بشكل أساسي:
the looser the curl pattern, the better the hair.
كلما كان نمط الشعر مرن كلما كان أفضل.
And we let these institutionalized ideas form a false sense of hierarchy
ونترك هذه الأفكار المؤسسية تشكل إحساسًا زائفًا بالتدرج
that would determine what was considered a good grade of hair
الذي يحدد الدرجة التي تصف الشعر الجيد
and what was not.
والشعر غير الجيد.
What's worse is that we let these false ideologies
والأسوأ من ذلك أننا تركنا هذه الاتجاهات الزائفة
invade our perception of ourselves,
تتدخل في طريقة نظرنا لأنفسنا،
and they still continue to infect our cultural identity
وتستمر في التأثير على هويتنا الثقافية
as African-American women today.
بصفتنا نساء أفريقيات أمريكيات اليوم.
So what did we do?
فماذا فعلنا؟
We went to the hair salon every six to eight weeks,
أننا نذهب إلى صالون الشعر كل 6 إلى 8 أسابيع،
without fail,
بدون انقطاع،
to subject our scalps to harsh straightening chemicals
لإخضاع فروة الرأس لمواد التنعيم الكيميائية القاسية
beginning at a very young age --
والتي تبدأ في سن صغيرة جدًا،
sometimes eight, 10 --
أحيانًا في سن 8 أو 10 سنوات،
that would result in hair loss,
مما يؤدي إلى تساقط الشعر،
bald spots,
وإحداث بقع الصلع،
sometimes even burns on the scalp.
وأحيانًا إحراق فروة الشعر.
We fry our hair at temperatures of 450 degrees Fahrenheit or higher
نحن نقلي شعرنا علي درجات حرارة من 450 درجة فهرنهايت أو أعلى
almost daily,
تقريبًا كل يوم،
to maintain the straight look.
للمحافظة على شكل الشعر الناعم.
Or we simply cover our hair up with wigs and weaves,
أو ببساطة نخفي شعرنا باستخدام الشعر المستعار،
only to let our roots breathe in private
فقط لكي نسمح لجذورنا أن تتنفس في الخفاء
where no one knows what's really going on under there.
حيث لا يعرف أحد ما يحدث بالفعل تحتها.
We adopted these practices in our own communities,
وقد اعتمدنا هذه الممارسات في مجتمعاتنا،
and so it's no wonder why today the typical ideal vision
ولذلك لا نتعجب من الرؤية المثالية والنموذجية
of a professional black woman,
التي تلقاها المرأة السمراء العاملة،
especially in corporate America,
وخاصة في الشركات الأمريكية،
tends to look like this,
وتميل لكي تبدو مثل هذا المظهر،
rather than like this.
بدلًا من هذا.
And she certainly doesn't look like this.
وهي بالتأكيد لا تبدو مثل هذا.
In September of this year,
في سبتمبر من هذه السنة،
a federal court ruled it lawful
قضت محكمة فيدرالية بمشروعية
for a company to discriminate against hiring an employee
ممارسة التمييز في شركة ما ضد تعيين موظف
based on if she or he wears dreadlocks.
إذا كان شعره أو شعرها على شكل ضفائر.
In the case,
وفي هذه الحالة،
the hiring manager in Mobile, Alabama
مديرة التوظيف في موبيل، ألاباما،
is on record as saying,
تقول في تسجيل صوتي،
"I'm not saying yours are messy,
"أنا لا أقول أن شعرك فوضوي،
but ...
ولكن ...
you know what I'm talking about."
أنت تعرف ما أتحدث عنه."
Well, what was she talking about?
حسنًا، عن ماذا كانت تتحدث؟
Did she think that they were ugly?
هل كانت تظن أنهم كانوا قبيحين؟
Or maybe they were just a little too Afrocentric
أو كانت تظهر عليهم السمة الأفريقية قليلًا
and pro-black-looking for her taste.
وأنهم مؤيدين لمظهر السود حسب ذوقها.
Or maybe it's not about Afrocentricity,
أو ربما لا يتعلق الأمر بالسمة الأفريقية،
and it's more just about it being a little too "urban"
وأنها تعبر بشكل أقل عن المظهر "الحضاري"
for the professional setting.
بالنسبة للبيئة المهنية.
Perhaps she had a genuine concern in that they looked "scary"
وربما كانت قلقة بشكل حقيقي من أنهم يبدون "مخيفين"
and that they would intimidate the clients and their customer base.
ويمكنهم أن يخيفوا العملاء وقاعدة زبائنها.
All of these words are ones that are too often associated
كل هذه الكلمات غالبًا ما ترتبط
with the stigma attached to natural hairstyles.
بوصمة العار اللاحقة بتصفيف الشعر الطبيعي.
And this ...
وهذا ...
this has got to change.
هذا يجب أن يتغير.
In 2013,
في 2013،
a white paper published by the Deloitte Leadership Center for Inclusion,
نشر مركز ديلويت القيادي للإدراج ورقة بيضاء
studied 3,000 individuals in executive leadership roles
تضمنت دراسة على 3000 فرد في أدوار القيادة التنفيذية
on the concept of covering in the workplace
على مفهوم التغطية في مكان العمل
based on appearance, advocacy, affiliation and association.
بناءً على المظهر الخارجي والتأييد والانتماء وتكوين الجمعيات.
When thinking about appearance-based covering,
عند التفكير في مبدأ تغطية المظهر الخارجي،
the study showed
أظهرت الدراسة
that 67 percent of women of color cover in the workplace
أن 67% من النساء ذوات البشرة الملونة يستترن في العمل
based on their appearance.
بسبب مظهرهن.
Of the total respondents who admitted to appearance-based covering,
من بين مجموع عدد المجيبين الذين اعترفوا بالتغطية بناءً على المظهر
82 percent said that it was somewhat to extremely important
صرح 82% بأنه من المهم نسبيًا
for them to do so for their professional advancement.
القيام بذلك من أجل تطورهم المهني.
Now, this is Ursula Burns.
الآن، هذه أورسيلا بيرنز.
She is the first African-American female CEO of a Fortune 500 company --
هي أول أنثى أمريكية أفريقية تعمل بصفتها مديرة تنفيذية لشركة مدرجة في فورشن 500،
of Xerox.
تابعة لزيروكس.
She's known by her signature look,
وهي معروفة بمظهرها الفريد،
the one that you see here.
الذي نراه هنا.
A short, nicely trimmed, well-manicured Afro.
شعر قصير مهذب، أفريقي مشذب.
Ms. Burns is what we like to call a "natural girl."
السيدة بيرنز هي ما نحب أن نسميها بـ"الفتاة الطبيعية."
And she is paving the way and showing what's possible
وهي تمهد الطريق و وتوضح إمكانية
for African-American women seeking to climb the corporate ladder,
سعي المرأة الأفريقية الأمريكية لتسلق السلم الوظيفي للشركات،
but still wishing to wear natural hairstyles.
ولكنها ما زالت ترغب في تصفيفة شعر طبيعية.
But today the majority of African-American women
ولكن اليوم أغلبية النساء الأفريقيات الأمريكيات
who we still look to as leaders, icons and role models,
اللاتي ننظر إليهن على أنهن قائدات وقدوات،
still opt for a straight-hair look.
مازلن يتطلعن إلى مظهر الشعر الناعم.
Now,
الآن،
maybe it's because they want to --
ربما لأنهن يردن ذلك،
this is authentically how they feel best --
هكذا يشعرن حقيقةً بأنهن أفضل حالًا،
but maybe --
ولكن ربما،
and I bet --
وأنا أراهن،
a part of them felt like they had to
أن جزء منهن أحسّ بضرورة فعل ذلك
in order to reach the level of success that they have attained today.
في سبيل الوصول إلى مستوى النجاح الذي وصلن له اليوم.
There is a natural hair movement that is sweeping the country
هناك حركة للشعر الطبيعي تكتسح البلاد
and also in some places in Europe.
وأيضًا في بعض الأماكن في أوروبا.
Millions of women are exploring what it means to transition to natural hair,
الملايين من النساء يختبرن معنى التحول إلى الشعر الطبيعي،
and they're cutting off years and years of dry, damaged ends
ويعملن على إنهاء سنوات عديدة من معاناة الأطراف الجافة والتالفة
in order to restore their natural curl pattern.
من أجل استعادة نمط التجعد الطبيعي.
I know because I have been an advocate and an ambassador for this movement
انا أعرف لأني كنت محامية الدفاع وسفيرة لدى هذه الحركة
for roughly the last three years.
لمدة آخر 3 سنوات تقريبًا.
After 27 years of excessive heat and harsh chemicals,
بعد 27 سنة من الحرارة المفرطة والكيماويات القاسية،
my hair was beginning to show extreme signs of wear and tear.
بدأ شعري في إظهار أقصى علامات الانهيار.
It was breaking off,
كان يتقطع،
it was thinning,
كان رقيقًا،
looking just extremely dry and brittle.
ويبدو جافًا للغاية وهشًا.
All those years of chasing that conventional image of beauty
كل هذة السنين من أجل مطاردة صورة الجمال التقليدية
that we saw earlier
التي رأيناها من قبل
was finally beginning to take its toll.
كان يأخذ حقه أخيرًا.
I wanted to do something about it,
كنت أريد أن أفعل شيئًا تجاه ذلك
and so I started what I called the "No Heat Challenge,"
ولذلك بدأت ما سميته "تحدي لا للحرارة،"
where I would refrain from using heat styling tools on my hair
حيث امتنعت عن استخدام أدوات تنعيم الشعر
for six months.
لمدة 6 أشهر.
And like a good millennial,
ومثل ألفية جيدة،
I documented it on social media.
قمت بتوثيقها على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I documented as I reluctantly cut off
وثقتها عندما قصصت على مضض
three to four inches of my beloved hair.
3 إلى 4 إنشات من شعري العزيز.
I documented as I struggled to master these natural hairstyles,
وثقتها كما كنت أناضل لإتقان تسريحات الشعر الطبيعية هذه،
and also as I struggled to embrace them
وأيضًا كما كنت أناضل لتقديرهم
and think that they actually looked good.
واعتقادي أن مظهرهم جيد.
And I documented as my hair texture slowly began to change.
ووثقت عندما كان نسيج شعري يتغير ببطء.
By sharing this journey openly,
بمشاركة هذه الرحلة على الملأ،
I learned that I was not the only woman going through this
تعلمت أني لم أكن المرأة الوحيدة التي تمر بهذا
and that in fact there were thousands and thousands of other women
وأنه في الحقيقة كان هناك الآلاف من النساء الأخريات
who were longing to do the same.
اللاتي يتشوقن ليقمن بالمثل.
So they would reach out to me and they would say,
لذلك كنّ يتواصلن معي ويقُلن،
"Cheyenne, how did you do that natural hairstyle
"شيني، كيف فعلت هذه التصفيفة الطبيعية للشعر
that I saw you with the other day?
التي رأيتك بها في ذلك اليوم؟
What new products have you started using
ما المنتجات الجديدة التي بدأتي باستخدامها
that might be a little better for my hair texture
التي قد تكون أفضل قليلًا لنسيج شعري
as it begins to change?"
كما كان يبدأ في التغير؟"
Or, "What are some of the natural hair routines
أو يسألن: "ما هو روتين الشعر الطبيعي
that I should begin to adopt to slowly restore the health of my hair?"
الذي يجب أن أتبعه لإعادة شعري الصحي تدريجيًا؟"
But I also found that there were a large number of women
ولكني أيضًا اكتشفت أنه هناك عدد كبير من النساء
who were extremely hesitant to take that first step
المترددات لأخذ الخطوة الأولى
because they were paralyzed by fear.
لأنهن كن عاجزات بسبب الخوف.
Fear of the unknown --
الخوف من المجهول،
what would they now look like?
كيف سيصبح شكلهن؟
How would they feel about themselves with these natural hairstyles?
كيف سيشعرن تجاه أنفسهن مع تصفيفات الشعر الطبيعية؟
And most importantly to them,
والأكثر أهمية لهن،
how would others view them?
كيف سينظر الآخرون إليهن؟
Over the last three years
على مدى السنوات الثلاث الماضية
of having numerous conversations with friends of mine
من إجراء محادثات عديدة مع أصدقائي
and also complete strangers from around the world,
وأيضًا مع غرباء تمامًا من جميع أنحاء العالم
I learned some really important things
تعلمت بعض الأمور المهمة جدًا
about how African-American women identify with their hair.
حول كيفية التعرف على النساء من أصل أفريقي خلال شعرهن.
And so when I think back
ولذلك حين أرجع لأفكر
to that hiring manager in Mobile, Alabama,
بكلام مديرة التوظيف في موبيل، ألاباما
I'd say, "Actually, no.
أريد ان أقول: "في الواقع، لا.
We don't know what you're talking about."
نحن لا نعرف ما الذي تتحدثين عنه."
But here are some things that we do know.
ولكن ها هي الأشياء التي نعرفها.
We know that when black women embrace their love for their natural hair,
نعرف أنه عندما تقدر النساء السمراوات حبهن لشعرهن الطبيعي
it helps to undo generations of teaching
هذا يساعد في إلغاء أجيال من التعليم
that black in its natural state is not beautiful,
أن شعر أصحاب البشرة السمراء في حالته الطبيعية ليس جميلًا،
or something to be hidden or covered up.
أو شيء يجب إخفاؤه أو تغطيته.
We know that black women express their individuality
نحن نعرف أن النساء السمراوات يعبرن عن فرديتهن
and experience feelings of empowerment
ويختبرن مشاعر من التمكين للمرأة
by experimenting with different hairstyles regularly.
من خلال اختبار تصفيفات مختلفة للشعر باستمرار
And we also know
ونحن أيضًا نعرف
that when we're invited to wear our natural hair in the workplace,
حينما نطالب باستخدام شعرنا الطبيعي في مجال العمل،
it reinforces that we are uniquely valued
يعزز ذلك تقدير الآخرين لنا
and thus helps us to flourish and advance professionally.
وبالتالي هذا يساعدنا على الازدهار والنهوض مهنيًا.
I leave you with this.
أترككم مع هذا.
In a time of racial and social tension,
في وقت توتر اجتماعي وعرقي،
embracing this movement
اتّباع هذه الحركة
and others like this
وغيرها من مثيلاتها
help us to rise above the confines of the status quo.
تساعدنا على الارتفاع فوق حدود الوضع الراهن
So when you see a woman with braids or locks draping down her back,
لذلك حين ترى امرأة بضفائر أو شعرها منسدلًا ورائها
or you notice your colleague
أو تلاحظ زميلتك
who has stopped straightening her hair to work,
التي توقفت عن فرد شعرها للعمل
do not simply approach her and admire
ببساطة لا تحاول الاقتراب منها وإبداء إعجابك
and ask her if you can touch it --
وتسألها إذا يمكنك لمسه،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Really appreciate her.
قدّرها حقًا.
Applaud her.
صفق لها.
Heck, even high-five her if that's what you feel so inclined to do.
بل حتى اضرب كفك بكفها إذا شعرت أن هذا ما تريد فعله.
Because this --
لأن هذا،
this is more than about a hairstyle.
هذا أكثر من مجرد تصفيفة شعر
It's about self-love and self-worth.
بل يتعلق بحب الذات وتقديرها.
It's about being brave enough
ويتعلق بكونك شجاعًا بما فيه الكفاية
not to fold under the pressure of others' expectations.
لعدم الوقوع تحت ضغط توقعات الآخرين.
And about knowing that making the decision to stray from the norm
ويتمحور حول معرفة أن اتخاذ قرار الانسحاب من القاعدة السائدة
does not define who we are,
لا يحدد شخصيتنا،
but it simply reveals who we are.
لكن يظهر ببساطة شخصيتنا.
And finally,
وأخيرًا،
being brave is easier
من السهل أن تصبح شجاعًا
when we can count on the compassion of others.
عندما لا نستطيع الاعتماد على تعاطف الآخرين.
So after today,
لذلك بعد اليوم،
I certainly hope that we can count on you.
أتمنى بالتأكيد أنه يمكننا الاعتماد عليكم.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)